

# **Daniele Giardiello**

Email address: daniele.giardiello1@gmail.com | Website:

https://danielegiardiello.github.io/

# ABOUT ME

Statistician with experience in research and statistical consulting in various international research institutes and private companies, with particular expertise in risk prediction model development, validation and deployment applied and methodological aspects. R / SAS / STATA / Python programmer with strong passion in statistics and data science. Extremely curious to actively learn new skills through challenging learning and working in team.

# EDUCATION AND TRAINING

14/11/2016 - 28/02/2021 Leiden, Netherlands

**DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY, PHD** Leiden University

My dissertation is available here

My dissertation is available here Public PhD defence on 8th September 2022 (video)

Supervisors: professor Marjanka K Schmidt & professor Ewout W Steyerberg

Co-supervisors: professor Michael Haumptmann & dr Maartje J Hooning

The research was funded by a grant from Alpe d'HuZes/Dutch Cancer Society (KWF Kankerbestrijding) under grant number A6C/6253.

Website <a href="https://scholarlypublications.universiteitleiden.nl/handle/1887/3455362">https://scholarlypublications.universiteitleiden.nl/handle/1887/3455362</a>

**Field of study** Medical Statistics, Epidemiology of breast cancer

**Thesis** Title of the dissertation: "Prediction of contralateral breast cancer - Statistical aspects and performance assessment"

10/2010 - 11/2012 Milan, Italy

MSC IN BIOSTATISTICS AND EXPERIMENTAL STATISTICS (SUMMA CUM LAUDE) University of Milan - Bicocca

Website https://en.unimib.it/

10/2007 - 09/2010 Milan, Italy

BSC IN STATISTICAL SCIENCE AND INFORMATION MANAGEMENT (SUMMA CUM LAUDE)

University of Milan - Bicocca

Website https://en.unimib.it/

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

06/2023 - 12/2023 Fully-remote

#### **SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST** MENARINI SILICON BIOSYSTEMS

Imaging analysis for circulating tumor cells (CTCs) using artificial intelligence methods such as deep learning

- Imaging annotation and segmentation
- Imaging classification
- · Assessing reproducibility, stability and diagnostic performance of laboratory tests

#### **SENIOR STATISTICIAN** CHIESI FARMACEUTICI

• Senior statistician for phase I-I-III trials (Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and idiophatic pulmunary fibrosis studies

Website https://www.chiesi.com/en/

06/04/2021 - 30/09/2022 Bolzano/Bozen, Italy

# BIOMEDICAL DATA SCIENTIST / BIOSTATISTICIAN (HOME-BASED) EURAC RESEARCH

Biomedical data scientist and statistical consultant in the field of biomedical research.

Research topics: epidemiology of COVID-19 and statistics modelling

Website https://www.eurac.edu/en

15/11/2016 - 28/02/2021 Amsterdam, Netherlands

### PHD CANDIDATE THE NETHERLANDS CANCER INSTITUTE (NKI)

Main goal: to develop, validate and assess the prediction performance and the clinical utility of a contralateral breast cancer risk prediction model using time-to-event models with competing risks using individual patient data (more than 100,000 patients) from multiple studies in presence of sporadic and systematic missing data.

#### Main activities:

- Data management and R/SAS/STATA programming also using High Performance Computing (HPC);
- Experience in Real World Data coming from different international sources;
- Statistical consulting for researchers and statistical teaching;
- Provide statistical reports using Rmarkdown and GitHub;
- External collaborator for two projects on behalf of STRATOS initiative (<a href="https://stratos-initiative.org/">https://stratos-initiative.org/</a>) working group TG6 (prediction models) and TG8 (survival analysis). The two papers are published in Annals of Internal medicine (<a href="https://sertation.org/">here</a>), and BMJ (<a href="https://sertation.org/">here</a>) and they are included in my PhD dissertation. I am also the main author and maintainer of the two corresponding GitHub repositories providing the R/ SAS/Python code available through this <a href="https://sertation.org/">website</a>.

**Business or Sector** Professional, scientific and technical activities | **Department** Molecular Pathology |

Website <a href="https://www.nki.nl/divisions/molecular-pathology/schmidt-m-group/">https://www.nki.nl/divisions/molecular-pathology/schmidt-m-group/</a>

01/07/2016 - 30/09/2016 Desio, Italy

STATISTICIAN OPIS SRL

Overall description: biostatistician working in clinical trials (phase II-III).

Main activities:

SAS programming; Revising Case Report Forms (CRFs); Providing listings, figures, and tables.

**Business or Sector** Professional, scientific and technical activities | **Address** 20832, Desio, Italy

Website <a href="https://opisresearch.com/">https://opisresearch.com/</a>

09/2014 - 06/2016 Milan, Italy

# **STATISTICIAN** ITALIAN NATIONAL CANCER INSTITUTE

- · Statistical consulting in medical research;
- R/SAS programming;
- Supporting research in statistical medical writing;

**Business or Sector** Professional, scientific and technical activities

**Department** Clinical Epidemiology and Clinical Trials organization | **Address** 20133, Milan, Italy |

Website https://www.istitutotumori.mi.it/en/home

# STATISTICIAN THE LOMBARDY AND EMILIA ROMAGNA EXPERIMENTAL ZOOTECHNIC INSTITUTE

- Statistical consulting and support for veterinary research;
- Epidemiological surveillance;
- Spatial statistics;

**Business or Sector** Professional, scientific and technical activities | **Address** 25124, Brescia, Italy |

Website <a href="https://www.izsler.it/">https://www.izsler.it/</a>

# LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **ITALIAN** 

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1
DUTCH	A2	A2	A2	A2	A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

# DIGITAL SKILLS

R | SAS | STATA | SPSS software | SQL | R Markdown | GitHUB | Python

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

# **PUBLICATIONS**

List of all publications in pubmed